<geeklist id="198923" termsofuse="http://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse">
<postdate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 17:01:32 +0000</postdate>
<postdate_timestamp>1446310892</postdate_timestamp>
<editdate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 16:27:03 +0000</editdate>
<editdate_timestamp>1446308823</editdate_timestamp>
<thumbs>119</thumbs>
<numitems>49</numitems>

<username>rangerx</username> 
<title>Solitaire Games on Your Table - November 2015</title>
<description>[center][imageid=2373684 medium] 
[size=18][b][COLOR=#660000]Welcome to

Solitaire Games [-]On Your Table[/-] In Your Turkey

November 2015![/COLOR][/b][/size][/center]

If you&#039;ve arrived here [thread=986303]via the subscription thread[/thread], welcome back!

If you&#039;ve just discovered this list through the front page, a subscription to a game that has been posted, from subscribing to another user, or through any other means, [b]WELCOME![/b]   We&#039;re glad to have you here!   Take a look around, make yourself at home, and join in on the fun!   Feel free to post games you&#039;ve played, comment on the games posted by others, and join the general discussion at the bottom of the page.


[floatright][b][u]Microbadges you might like:[/u][/b]
[microbadge=1714] - Solitaire Gamer
[microbadge=30018] - Solitaire Games on Your Table
[microbadge=6631] - Gaming is best solo
[microbadge=33779] - 1 Player Guild Member
[microbadge=33781] - Solitaire Gamer
[microbadge=21495] - [url=http://boardgamegeek.com/microbadge/21495]1 Player Podcast[/url]
[microbadge=17861][microbadge=25367][microbadge=29273] - Rallyman!
[/floatright]
[b][u]Useful links for the Solo BGGer:[/u][/b]
[b][guild=1303][/guild][/b]
Home Base for solitaire gaming.

[b][thread=986303][/thread][/b]
Subscribe to make sure you never miss a month.

[b][geeklist=183705][/geeklist][/b]
The [i]only[/i] way to play multiplayer solitaire!

[b][geeklist=166714][/geeklist][/b]
A [i]&quot;support group&quot;[/i] for the [i]&quot;unfortunate victims&quot;[/i] of these monthly lists. When this list costs you money, go here to tell us all about it.

[b][geeklist=182682][/geeklist][/b]
An ongoing list where you can give and get games.

[b][geeklist=175019][/geeklist][/b]
Got some money burning a hole in your pocket and need some good recommendations? 

[b][geeklist=182648][/geeklist][/b]
The best of the best in solo gaming (for 2014). [thread=1453487]Nominations for 2015 have already started![/thread]  Voted on by you, created and curated by our very own 
[user=kerskine][/user]

[b][geeklist=49479][/geeklist][/b]
Solo rules for multiplayer games.
[center][IMG]http://airquipinc.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Separator_line-01-01.png[/IMG][/center]
[size=12][b][u]Game Ratings:[/u][/b][/size]
It has become somewhat of a custom to give a brief set of ratings for any game that gets posted here to give others an idea of what to expect.  It would be really great to see that continue! Share your impressions of the game you played with everyone through thumbs up/down commentary, ratings, a short review, etc... It&#039;s your post, you do you.


[size=12][b][u]November brings Thanksgiving![/u][/b][/size]

...so for this month I&#039;ll be awarding a little bit of :gg: to everyone who posts about something they are thankful for that is related to solo gaming on BGG in general: a user whose file(s) that helped you with a game, the 1-Player guild for being a great community or especially any specific members/regulars. I&#039;ll warm up the yams and start carving the turkey while you tell your tale.

For example, I&#039;m [i]very thankful[/i] to

[user=woelf]

for sending me the code for this header (back in Feb!) so I didn&#039;t have to start from scratch!

Please add something to your post to make your :star:[b]THANKS[/b]:star: stand out so I don&#039;t miss it. Despite how busy this thread gets I do manage to read and thumb every entry each month but even so I do miss things once in awhile.
[center][IMG]http://airquipinc.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Separator_line-01-01.png[/IMG][/center]
[b][u]Future SGoyT hosts include such users as:[/u][/b]
[i]December 2015[/i] - [user=mikolajl] Mikolaj Laczynski[/user]
[i]January 2016[/i] - [user=suzyvitale] Suzy Vitale[/user]
[i]February 2016[/i] - [user=Woelf] Kyle Woelf[/user]
[i]March 2016[/i] - [user=pusherman42] Jack Bennett[/user]
</description>


	<item id="4248263" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="173064" 			
			objectname="Leaving Earth"
			username="rangerx" 
			postdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 17:01:04 +0000" 
			editdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 17:01:04 +0000"
			thumbs="51"
						imageid="2624698">
	<body>I finished October with this game and I&#039;ll be starting November with it.

I posted some of my initial [listitem=4247032]impressions[/listitem] in last months SGOYT list and promised some pictures for this month.  I apologize in advance for the difference in quality between some of these, I took some in the evening in lower light.

First, I love the artwork used in this game, it&#039;s deliciously retro.  I also picked up the Mercury expansion with the base game.

The box is like a small shoe-box, you&#039;ll need to cut along the edge of the box art to open it up. I decided to leave a small hinge but I&#039;m sure that might wear over time.

Box is ready to be cut open...
[imageid=2733068]

Box contents, everything was neatly packed in separate baggies...
[imageid=2733067]

The bits, I love these bits, they have a handcrafted feel to them. Each wooden bit is etched giving them a nice detail I really appreciate.
[imageid=2733066]

There&#039;s paper money in the box, it&#039;s rather nice actually. Many people aren&#039;t into paper money but I like these notes.
[imageid=2733064]

The game calendar (20 turns) and Space Agency cards.
[imageid=2733062]

Advancement cards, as I mentioned last month just one had a blank back on it. (Joeseph already contacted me about it too.)
[imageid=2732531]

Each agency has it&#039;s own Spacecraft cards and also pictured are the Mission cards, the Mission cards have different colored card back to help ease differentiation of the level of difficulty.
[imageid=2733061]

The location cards are very nice and create what is essentially the game board. Large tile cards with some variation for locations that can be explored.
[imageid=2733060]

The Component and Astronaut cards are smaller, these are played on the Spacecraft cards during the game.
[imageid=2733059]

The Outcome cards are also smaller and are played on the Advancement cards. You can kind of see the ratio of successes to major &amp; minor failure cards here.
[imageid=2733058]

And finally, the Mercury expansion contains some extra locations, missions and sample cards.
[imageid=2733057]

I&#039;m going to be terribly busy the rest of today but will be playing this again tomorrow (first day in November this side of the Prime Meridian).

:star:[b]THANKS![/b]:star:
I want to again say thanks to the designer:
[user=buffalohat][/user]

for doing a wonderful job diffusing the supply issue after the 1st edition sold out and assuring people that their copies were on the way. Heck of a PR job sir!  Thanks for the game!





</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4248271" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="168274" 			
			objectname="Mistfall"
			username="eastwoodk" 
			postdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 17:08:32 +0000" 
			editdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 17:08:32 +0000"
			thumbs="32"
						imageid="2410035">
	<body>All setup and ready to go tomorrow as I enter my birthday month!!!! :D</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4248289" 
			objecttype="geeklist"
			subtype="" 
			objectid="198905" 			
			objectname="Barteus Con 2015: The convention for the rest of us"
			username="airjudden" 
			postdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 17:15:15 +0000" 
			editdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 17:15:15 +0000"
			thumbs="62"
						imageid="2732446">
	<body>For the month of November, I will be playing 30 solitaire games in 30 days.  Click the link below for the details and subscribe to it, as I will update it daily and add pics, reports, etc, with commentary from The Rock, Mr. T, and T-Rex (a.k.a. the hecklers):

[url=https://www.boardgamegeek.com/geeklist/198905/barteus-con-2015]Barteus-Con 2015: The convention for the rest of us![/url]

[ImageID=2732446large]</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4248300" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="180585" 			
			objectname="T.I.M.E Stories: The Marcy Case"
			username="Ikim" 
			postdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 17:23:58 +0000" 
			editdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 17:23:58 +0000"
			thumbs="19"
						imageid="2617644">
	<body>I have this ready on my table: I just have to wait the girls go out trick-or-treating, so I can have some alone-time.

Prepare for lots of [-]spoilers[/-]…. 

No, no worries… just kidding… It sure LOOKS good: lets hope the hype is founded! </body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4248349" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="33924" 			
			objectname="Nightfighter"
			username="swamphamster" 
			postdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 17:57:47 +0000" 
			editdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 18:08:43 +0000"
			thumbs="29"
						imageid="1014708">
	<body>I&#039;m very thankful for/to...

[b]Phil Sabin[/b] who wrote solo rules for Nightfighter and posted them on BGG.  His rules take a very good 2-player game (with one player as a &quot;controller&quot; behind a screen) to an excellent [b]solitaire[/b] game.

:tankard: A toast to Phil Sabin

:thumbsup: challenging.
:thumbsup: great replayability.
:thumbsdown: While I thoroughly enjoy the game which quite accurately mirrors WWII night fighting, I realize solo &quot;hunting in the dark&quot; may not be everyone&#039;s [i][b]&#039;slice of turkey&#039;[/b][/i].
</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4248352" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="183963" 			
			objectname="Invaders from Dimension X!"
			username="koinskyz" 
			postdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 18:03:05 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 05:23:40 +0000"
			thumbs="46"
						imageid="2664729">
	<body>I spent most of my vacation week, lying in bed. 

I was doing some usual carpentry job, made a bad movement and tore a muscle in my back (not sure it&#039;s English, but you&#039;ve got the idea). Well, the consequences were that I could hardly walk or even stay comfortably sitting at a table to play large - and/or long - games for the most part of the week.

So, I played one [b]small[/b] - very manageable in a bed - game: the newest (to my knowledge) Hermann Luttmann&#039;s game.

And I liked it a LOT! Not very deep, but very original and funny wargame against unpredictable Aliens. 
It will not stand as my game of the year. However, it&#039;s definitely my game of the week[i] (at least, for the previous reasons ;))[/i]. 

As I had nothing to do, I even wrote a short review. It&#039;s [-]pending approval. I&#039;ll update this post with the link when it will be[/-] available [url=http://boardgamegeek.com/article/20790918#20790918] here [/url]if you wish to read more info on the game.

Well, on Monday, I&#039;ll be back to work and it was inconceivable to leave my mountains without playing outdoor, at least once, surrounded by the melezes with their lovely autumnal hues (I love those trees, although I never knew their English&#039;s name. The scientific name is Larix European). 

Went to a lake above the village (it must be the first time of my life I&#039;m driving there instead of walking there!) and enjoyed Fall in all its splendor :D

[imageid=2733153large]</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4248358" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="84465" 			
			objectname="Ottoman Sunset"
			username="Hubble123" 
			postdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 18:05:39 +0000" 
			editdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 18:05:39 +0000"
			thumbs="44"
						imageid="1715324">
	<body>Ottoman Sunset -- an excellent solitaire game.

And...following its post-WWI collapse, the country is now called...

:T::U::R::K::E::Y:

Can&#039;t get any more Thanksgiving related than that!</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4248399" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="29109" 			
			objectname="Dust"
			username="ad79" 
			postdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 18:33:00 +0000" 
			editdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 18:33:00 +0000"
			thumbs="24"
						imageid="280668">
	<body>[b]November out of the dust challenge.[/b]

Play a game you own, but have not played so far this year.

Mention it in a comment and a random entry wins 23 GG.</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4248403" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="161936" 			
			objectname="Pandemic Legacy"
			username="joestin" 
			postdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 18:38:07 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:41:12 +0000"
			thumbs="29"
						imageid="2452831">
	<body>I&#039;m

[size=24]:heart::bacon::heart::bacon::heart:THANKFUL:heart::bacon::heart::bacon::heart:[/size]

to Jason for hosting this month&#039;s list. :whistle:

Also, I&#039;ll be starting up Pandemic: Legacy most likely tonight. Don&#039;t worry, my entries will be spoiler free.

[b]Update:[/b] I cheated and sneaked in game 1 during my daughter&#039;s extended nap. I&#039;m tracking my play on a geeklist, but will keep things private for now. I rolled with the Scientist, Researcher, and Dispatcher which are kind of a dream team if you ask me. Sure enough, I won game 1 and will move on.

As far as the &quot;legacy&quot; stuff that occurred... it was pretty cool. Already thinking this will be a winner. I&#039;m playing to the fullest as well. Already ripped up a card and applied a couple stickers.</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4248438" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="173064" 			
			objectname="Leaving Earth"
			username="suzyvitale" 
			postdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 19:07:23 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 02:30:36 +0000"
			thumbs="58"
						imageid="2624698">
	<body>I&#039;m so thankful for SGOYT and the 1P Guild, you all have made my gaming life a even more wonderful thing.  Thank you for spending all of my money too.

I&#039;m thankful for thoughtful game designers like Joe Fatula who put together this gorgeous game, Leaving Earth.  (Which I will be playing here shortly...)

I&#039;m thankful for my husband who loves to game with me and who has a very high tolerance for this &quot;solo gaming thing&quot; I&#039;ve been up to this year.  And the ever growing solo game collection.

I&#039;m thankful for IKEA bookshelves, otherwise I have no idea how I would store my huge collection of awesomeness.

And, finally, I&#039;m thankful for the roof over my head, the food on my table (and the tea kettle singing in the kitchen), and the company of excellent friends and family in my life.  :heart: 


**Update**

Finally got the game set up.  HOLY COW this has got to be one of the most beautiful games in my collection.  The art is absolutely spot on.  I might be the world&#039;s biggest NASA geek, so I&#039;m kinda freaking out here.  I will share some of this eye candy with you.

[imageid=2733319 medium]

[imageid=2733323 medium]

[imageid=2733326 medium]

[imageid=2733333 medium]

I&#039;ve read through most of the rulebook now and it&#039;s a thematic gem.  I especially appreciate how the designer handles funding.  (Oh my friend, you truly understand how the US Government&#039;s R&amp;D budgets work...)  Now my brain is tired after all that reading (hey, it was a pretty intense week at work for me), so I&#039;m leaving it set up and taking a break.  I hope to get at least one play in today.  


**Update #2**

Really, really enjoyed this game.  First off, I think I found a hidden joke in this game... (If only Wally Schirra had the &quot;heal all astronauts&quot; ability on the Apollo 7 mission!)

[imageid=2733644 medium]

I played the Easy level, 5 easy missions.  Developing technologies and testing your technology/components is very thematic and a great mechanic in the game.  Here are my early technology cards:

[imageid=2733646 medium]

[o]Getting the Juno rockets technology developed and fully tested early on was very helpful in accomplishing early missions.[/o]

There were cigars all around when I got a probe in space.

[imageid=2733648 medium]

More cigars when I surveyed the surface of the moon.

[imageid=2733649 medium]

And cigars and whiskey when I landed on the lunar surface.

[imageid=2733650 medium]


:thumbsup: This game takes a lot of careful planning in order to successfully complete missions, so that when you do, it feels very satisfying.  

:thumbsup: The most thematically accurate game in my collection.  I can&#039;t praise the game enough for this.

:thumbsup: Math-y, but not overwhelmingly so.  You definitely want a calculator handy, if you aren&#039;t great at doing math in your head.  I found the math to be part of the theme as well...if I&#039;m really running NASA, then you better believe I&#039;m running these kinds of numbers all the time.  Also, it kinda makes you feel smart.

:thumbsup: Excellent high quality components.  BEAUTIFUL art, excellent graphic design.

:thumbsup: A solid, immersive solo experience.  Hours went by and I had no idea.

:thumbsup: Simple, straightforward game play with loads of decisions each turn.  Your constraints are mostly budgetary (painfully realistic!).

:thumbsup: The technology development mechanic is pure genius.

:thumbsdown: Wish it wasn&#039;t paper money.  Wish I didn&#039;t have to cut the sticker in order to open the box.  (Extremely minor complaints here.)

:thumbsdown: There are a lot of rules &quot;details&quot; that are missing from the rulebook.  A printed FAQ could be helpful in a reprint.  I had to go to the BGG rules forum several times to get rules clarifications.


I&#039;m really glad I bought this game.  It was definitely worth the wait.  The theme alone makes this a winner for me, but the game play is so good.  I&#039;m looking forward to playing a more challenging solo game with the harder missions, now that I know how to play.</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4248482" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="123955" 			
			objectname="Thunderbolt Apache Leader"
			username="Longbombed" 
			postdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 19:56:41 +0000" 
			editdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 19:56:41 +0000"
			thumbs="41"
						imageid="1296959">
	<body>In keeping with this months theme, I am :star:[b]THANKFUL[/b]:star: to [user=ryanmobile][/user] for introducing me to the 1 Player Guild, but more specifically, SGoYT when he was being kind to me in the [thing=123955][/thing] forums. He was the first user to tip me, giving me my first badge for this game, and it&#039;s been in my #1 slot since then, and that was a couple years ago, I think. SGoYT has been one of my favorite online &#039;things&#039; to do. I love reading others stories of their games, and even getting to know a few of them. It&#039;s helped me more than any game&#039;s forums in learning or understanding certain games and aspects I having difficulties with. Like we say... nicest place on the net.

 So with that, I&#039;ll be pulling this gem out this month and giving it a good go, all in thanks to Ryan for getting me here.</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4248484" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="144189" 			
			objectname="Fire in the Lake"
			username="Rimush" 
			postdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 19:57:43 +0000" 
			editdate="Sat, 31 Oct 2015 19:57:43 +0000"
			thumbs="28"
						imageid="2083738">
	<body>Got this Bad Boy last month and have a 4 player game scheduled for 9th Nov.

HOWEVER, I am intending to play it solo in NOVEMBER using the Bots provided.

In preparation I have watched Hamburger Hill, Apocalypse Now, Platoon, Full Metal Jacket, The Deer Hunter and We Were Soldiers.

I&#039;m now going to dig some tunnels in my back garden...

[q]The Horror, The Horror![/q]</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4248836" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="168679" 			
			objectname="Flip City"
			username="And bec" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 01:09:28 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 01:09:28 +0000"
			thumbs="20"
						imageid="2499620">
	<body>[b]Result:[/b] Lost as the supply deck ran out

[b]Thoughts:[/b] Fun first play through of the solo game. I got to 6 points (out of 8 needed)with about 6 cards left in the supply and thought i would easily win this. I had too many unhappiness cards and not enough point cards. Lesson learnt!

[b]Rating, based on this game:[/b] very good - 8

[b]Average rating of the last 5 games*[/b] n/a



[size=5]* Since 29/10/15 when the 2015 people choice list was submitted. [/size]

</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4248856" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="70519" 			
			objectname="Cruel Necessity"
			username="jbetz45453" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 01:36:42 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 01:36:42 +0000"
			thumbs="27"
						imageid="1818617">
	<body>I will be setting this up tomorrow and play it a bit each day as I play the long game. My first 2 plays of this saw little success. I am hoping the third time is the charm.</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249083" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="154842" 			
			objectname="Eldritch Horror: Forsaken Lore"
			username="sixthecat" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 05:13:08 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 05:13:08 +0000"
			thumbs="32"
						imageid="1940723">
	<body>[size=18][COLOR=#CC3300][b]Happy All Saint&#039;s Day![/b][/COLOR][/size]

[IMG]http://www.johncoulthart.com/images/oldones/yig.jpg[/IMG]

Diana, Trish, and Jaqueline had a go versus Yig for Halloween.
Think I&#039;ve been running this Eldritch Horror tradition for 3 years now.

Things went pretty well. The dames solved the first mystery, and were close to solving the second. Trish had the 2 allies needed to solve it when...

[IMG]https://s3.amazonaws.com/rapgenius/backstabber.jpg[/IMG]

They both turned on her and stabbed her in the back. So not only did she lose the health, but bloody traitor allies were gone too.

[IMG]http://www.marvunapp.com/Appendix/amariner6.jpg[/IMG]

This delayed things until Diana got the serpent crown and got it to Trish, but with that and a couple wasted turns Trish finally got the 2 needed allies again. 

Trish&#039;s ability to gain a Clue if she had none, and Jaqueline&#039;s ability to trade Clues with anyone anywhere was abused often! :devil:

[IMG]https://img1.etsystatic.com/000/0/5287082/il_fullxfull.328835283.jpg[/IMG]

It finally came down to the gals going to Mexico and solving the final mystery. Two failed turns lead to them finally completing the final mystery......right as--

[size=18][b]YIG AWAKENS![/b][/size]

[ImageID=2733733 medium]
ENDING SHOT (Note: the hearts and brains signify how much damage/insanity taken rather than hit points left.)

The gals battled it out. Diana had enough conditions to cripple a horse.
But with her shiny sword, she was able to deal the final blow.

[IMG]https://8bitscholar.files.wordpress.com/2010/07/a_winner_is_you_1024.jpg?w=300&amp;h=225[/IMG]


</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249117" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="135382" 			
			objectname="Shadowrun: Crossfire"
			username="joestin" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 06:19:05 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 06:19:05 +0000"
			thumbs="28"
						imageid="2060466">
	<body>[listitem=4249116]Mission: Crossfire[/listitem]

Run Journal:
[imageid=2733930 medium]

Um, yes please. Free 9-cost cards are fantastic. Getting two other 9-costs into your decks is also fantastic.

This game went really well for the most part. I set up Scene 3 with only 2 Crossfire cards discarded. Rex was staggered at one point, but in a great turn of fortune, I drew the &quot;Top Shelf&quot; Crossfire card right after and he healed right up.

Mission result: Success
Karma: 3

Cumulative Karma:
Jet - 6
Rex - 6

This game continues to impress. The cardplay is incredible. I&#039;ve gotten used to a lot of weapon cards, especially for my dwarf, but this game, literally TWO came out of the Black Market.</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249169" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="170225" 			
			objectname="DRCongo"
			username="gentle" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 08:39:15 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 17:34:38 +0000"
			thumbs="29"
						imageid="2345066">
	<body>I nearly backed this game on kickstarter but somehow decided against it. It sounded very interesting but it looked somewhat outdated with the paper money and the graphics. But to be fair, that works really well for this game and in a weird way adds to the charm and theme of the game for me now.


[imageid=2733964medium]

Anyway, I&#039;ve been playing this game all morning. This game is broken into four different levels. Each level adds another layer to the game. The solo game uses all four levels but I decided to play a two player game, starting with the easiest level. Thats a pretty straightforward game, you build industries and try to sell it for the hightest prize. Pretty neat, but nothing special.

Then I moved on to add the next layer to the game, the action cards and the rebellions. That made the game quite a bit more complex, since you can&#039;t develop cities or build transport while there are still unsurpressed insurgents in the province and nothing can be produced there. Made for a much more interesting game.

Now I&#039;m about to set it up again, adding the next layer of rules, advancing to the government game. Now there are three ministers in play, the defence, interior and finance minister and you can elect one of them.

I like this kind of slowly adding rules to the game till you come to the complete game. I don&#039;t think I made a single mistake in the first two games, since it starts out as pretty basic. And in adding new stuff, gameplay doesn&#039;t get repetitive, keeping me away from playing it again.

[b]edit[/b]: I&#039;ve now played a game using all the rules and I have to say I&#039;m really impressed with the game. Its really great! Very happy to have bought this. The easiest way to play it is just simple and a decent game, adding stuff to it layer by layer keeps making it better and better. I can&#039;t wait to play the full game again, this time using the solo rules.</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249217" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="100901" 			
			objectname="Flash Point: Fire Rescue"
			username="And bec" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 09:47:55 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 09:47:55 +0000"
			thumbs="20"
						imageid="1129370">
	<body>
[b]Result:[/b] Won, saving 7 people and not losing 1!!!

[b]Thoughts:[/b] Played the advanced game on the recruit level. Randomly drew the Rescue Specialist and Chief (cant remember exact name). It was obvious to just use the RS to get people, considering gets 7 AP for moving and the chief gave her 2 more AP on his turn to move. The chief just took care of the fires. Was a comfortable victory in the end! I didn&#039;t find it challenging, but i had a great team combo and was on easiest level!

[b]Rating, based on this game:[/b] Good - 7</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249221" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="123160" 			
			objectname="Battle For Souls"
			username="repairmanjack" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 10:02:58 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 14:27:08 +0000"
			thumbs="24"
						imageid="1793962">
	<body>I was lucky enough to win this, earlier in the year, in the generosity thread (with the great odds that I was the sole entrant). I&#039;ve had nine plays of it, solo, now and I&#039;m still in love with it. 

You&#039;re playing poker hands from either a temptation or virtue deck (augmented by some other decks) - depending on which side you wish to play -  to try and elevate the soul points of the contested departed so you can win them with the playing of a Reap card. Souls need a value of four points, measured by the dice, or they vanish to Purgatory. It&#039;s a two-player combat game, effectively, with an in the box solitaire variant. It plays almost identically, except you&#039;re managing your hand against a couple of constraints - and trying to beat a set score. 

Played two games, scoring 19 and then 15 points. 35 is considered decent. :cry:

This is all about the theme and the artwork, using Renaissance works to bring everything to life. It&#039;s damn near perfect as a solo game, and I say that as someone who typically abhors the beat a score mechanism. 

[imageid=2734008large]
Initial solitaire set-up. 

[imageid=2734014large]
Full-house! Patience is a virtue. </body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249255" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="2866" 			
			objectname="The London Game"
			username="ian_07720169619" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 10:45:12 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 10:45:12 +0000"
			thumbs="13"
						imageid="107790">
	<body>I ended last month with a game I hadn&#039;t played in years and I&#039;m going to start this month with another game I haven&#039;t played all year. This game was my backup game for my 10x10 challenge as I assumed I&#039;d easily get 10 plays done with my friends. They all own the game after playing my copy but even they haven&#039;t played it that much this year.

The game is really not suited to solitaire play (and it makes no claims to support it). The whole game revolves around hidden information (your 6 destinations) but every time you change lines you have to draw a hazard card that often allows other players to move you to another station on the board. In a standard game this is fine as the other players may have an idea of where you are heading but do not know. In a solo game it can be difficult to pretend you do not know where the other player is heading.

Anyway, I played a 2 player game with both players opting to start at the same station. Player 1 visited their 6 destinations before player 2 had visited their 5th but, with some good placement of station closures and some lucky hazard cards, player 2 managed to catch up before player 1 made it back to the starting station. Both players struggled to get to the station and found themselves both enjoying a pint in Greenwich while looking at the Cutty Sark. they both got to within 1 space of the starting station, which was blocked, so the first of them to roll a 6 would win the game. Player 1 managed the task first and won.

:thumbsup: - The game plays quickly and is over before you get too annoyed with the hazard cards.
:thumbsdown: - Not as fun without other players to interact with.
:thumbsdown: - Very limited variety in the stations and hazards.</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249278" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="60435" 			
			objectname="Rallyman"
			username="koinskyz" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 11:36:12 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 11:36:12 +0000"
			thumbs="25"
						imageid="1114034">
	<body>In the spirit of this month&#039;s theme ...


I&#039;d like to thank 

[user=Shaungamer]

for organizing the 

[IMG]http://cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2362830.jpg[/IMG]
which is such a nice monthly activity. It&#039;s a lovely corner into this guild lovely corner... :D


Also, I&#039;d like to thank him personally for the numerous friendly reminders I received (I assume it&#039;s an automatic GM, hope so for you Shaun...) few days before the deadline, because - most of the time - I&#039;m late to run my stage in order to figure in the last ranks of the challenge :)


</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249486" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="35815" 			
			objectname="A Touch of Evil: The Supernatural Game"
			username="crazybear" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 14:19:36 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 18:31:03 +0000"
			thumbs="22"
						imageid="326493">
	<body>I played through A Touch of Evil basic board against the dreaded Vampire. It was a ton of fun and I recorded my sessions so that you can watch them if you want! I link the videos below as they are approved.

Videos:
1. Also found at: https://boardgamegeek.com/video/82368/touch-evil-supernatural-game/crazybears-den-touch-evil-play-2-episode-1
[youtube=https://youtu.be/s_QwRs-W48Y]




Again, I have to say this game is near the top if not at the top of my favorites list.

:thumbsup: Enjoy the theme!
:thumbsup: Love the way the game plays and the random nature of it.
:thumbsup: Really enjoy the story. :)</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249520" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="166317" 			
			objectname="Time of Soccer"
			username="patton55" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 14:46:43 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 14:46:43 +0000"
			thumbs="29"
						imageid="2420740">
	<body>Starting the month off right. This is such a good game solo, with the non-player stuff built right into it. Plays pretty fast. Love this game and I&#039;m not even really a soccer fan (I&#039;m a baseball and American football fan first), but my wife (born and raised in Poland) converted me to actually enjoying soccer--just as I converted her to loving baseball. 

[imageid=2734325 large]

And I&#039;m even more excited as Minnesota will be getting a Major League soccer team (Minnesota United) they just agreed to build the new stadium right in my back door, St. Paul. </body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249527" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="28044" 			
			objectname="Pocket Civ"
			username="Lhowser" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 14:48:34 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 14:48:34 +0000"
			thumbs="21"
						imageid="507528">
	<body>So, thanks to some pretty incredible deals at cowcow and artscow, as well as some great guides to creating/designing/printing cards from those sites on the various boards - I was able to get some games I&#039;ve been looking at for a while. (but as I can&#039;t keep off the site now, I don&#039;t know if it&#039;s a blessing or a curse. :zombie:)

In September I had almost burned out of wargaming, with frustration at one of the games I was attempting to play, so last month chose to play things I KNOW I like. (Thank you to all of the 1-Player Guild for listening to my struggles and adding their similar feelings) I had a blast playing the [family=9547][/family] multiple times and really seeing how the games work or evolve over time.

I was able to print a nice set of advancement/wonder cards and event cards for Pocket Civ.  After looking through the rules, I really didn&#039;t NEED to advancement/wonder cards - only if I was planning on pimping out the game completely.  I guess it&#039;s nice to have them, though.

The game doesn&#039;t look like it takes THAT long to play, so I should easily get multiple plays through of the game, as well as Multiple plays of the other games I printed.
</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249531" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="43693" 			
			objectname="Delve the Card Game"
			username="Lhowser" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 14:49:37 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 15:24:32 +0000"
			thumbs="19"
						imageid="498963">
	<body>Another cowcow/artscow deck I was able to make.

[b] Play 1 &amp; 2 [/b]

So, this game is designed as a dungeon crawl.  You choose one of four standard Heroes (Rogue/Fighter/Wizard/Cleric) with a given vitality/health (which also is your attack value,) choose a weapon/item which adds to your attack, and then shuffle the rest of the deck of items/monsters.  This deck then becomes your &quot;dungeon.&quot;  You explore by simply turning over cards and comparing your attack value to the monsters you encounter.  If your attack is more, you win.  If it equals or is less, you lose and take that amount of damage to your hero.  The object is to get through the entire &quot;dungeon.&quot;

That&#039;s it.

And really - that&#039;s about it.

My first play-thru I randomly chose the cleric, who heals one for every vanquished monster.  I also chose the Saint&#039;s Mace with a +4 attack value.  I was able to get a healing potion (+2 heal) and a holy symbol (Automatically kills Undead) right off the bat, so I pretty much burned my way through the deck and won rather easily.

The second time I lost pretty easily as well with the same Hero and weapon.

Reading through the game&#039;s forums, I discovered I needed to have printed TWO Healing Potions and TWO Goblin cards!  (The cards I found were only 52 in number, so I made two &quot;instruction cards&quot; with extremely tiny rules on them that I can barely make out - it was my first time using artscow.)  So maybe the extra healing potions will give you SOME chance to get through the deck.

:thumbsdown: There&#039;s really not a whole lot to the game, and really almost zilch strategy to it.  Choose a hero, get a weapon, and turn over cards. As you can only hold two items at a time, I suppose there&#039;s a tiny bit of strategy involved in choosing the items to hold, but other than that....
:thumbsup: Simple.  Easy to play. Short. Games take however long it takes you to turn card over card through an entire (or less) deck of cards.
:thumbsup: If you can get a nice deck made, this is a nice mindless stocking stuffer for a gamer friend.
:thumbsdown: That&#039;s it.  That&#039;s the game.  That&#039;s it.

I have another artscow/cowcow purchase coming to me sometime.  I&#039;ll have to make the extra cards to see if that makes the game any more winnable.
</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249535" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="42651" 			
			objectname="Airborne In Your Pocket: Free Trial Version"
			username="Lhowser" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 14:50:41 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 14:50:41 +0000"
			thumbs="14"
						imageid="537084">
	<body>The other artscow/cowcow decks I was able to make.  Including some of the expansions.</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249562" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="172220" 			
			objectname="Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Temple of Elemental Evil Board Game"
			username="Longbombed" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 15:01:27 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 15:01:27 +0000"
			thumbs="19"
						imageid="2496558">
	<body>Continued my campaign into scenario 4. The warrior, ranger, and cleric. Down into the dungeon they went to pursue the dreaded cults that were plaguing the lands. I took a heavy beating this time, realizing that I hadn&#039;t in the past due to the amount of HP markers my heroes were accumulating. Luckily I found 2 healing potions from some dead monsters, and my cleric really put her healing skill to the test. I squeaked out a victory where I got to face a really interesting mechaniced villain, the salamander.

Funny thing, I posted before about the bland base colours of the figs, and [user=scarge][/user] recommended I base coat them to give some clarity and make the details pop. I primed 3 bigger figs in black and 1 in grey (earth elemental), and they looked great! It inspired me to play this 4th scenario. Little did I know, that the end villain was one of the figs I had based... and it wasn&#039;t dry yet!! So when the heroes found the villain&#039;s lair (tile), I had to wait a bit for the primer to dry, lol.

Still having fun with this game, which is nice and surprising. I played [thing=59946][/thing] a few times with a buddy, and borrowed it for some solo and really, really didn&#039;t like the system. When I bought this one, I shook my head when I got home. I paid $80 for a game with a system I didn&#039;t like, yet I left [thing=146652][/thing] sitting on the shelf at my FLGS. I actually was okay with the fact that if I didn&#039;t like it, as before, I would have some great figs for my upcoming D&amp;D campaign. So the fact that I&#039;m enjoying it, is a nice surprise.

I&#039;m going to do my best with some of the figs, and get some base coating going on, then I think I&#039;ll do some &#039;dipping&#039; wash and see how they turn out. I&#039;d like to try simplifying my monsters and minions of games in hopes of getting a set finished. Most my attempts leave me with some great figs, but only 1/3 or 1/2 of the game completed before burnout kicks in. I usually spend a lot of time on each making them hero quality rather than troop quality. Hope this one works out!</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249563" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="161936" 			
			objectname="Pandemic Legacy"
			username="patton55" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 15:02:19 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 15:02:19 +0000"
			thumbs="25"
						imageid="2452831">
	<body>Spoiler Alert? I don&#039;t think so, I just took a couple pictures of my game/campaign in progress, so they are all out of context. 

What can I say about this game? Absolutely freaking fantastic. The regular basic old Pandemic was okay. It had been sitting on my shelf for over a year untouched. But I won First Minnesota&#039;s [thing=40354][/thing] Tournament, and took my winnings and bought this, because Joel Eddy said it was his top game of the year. So I decided to take a chance. 

It&#039;s very tense, you play each month of the year, and things mutate and change, and new things get added as you go along, so each game becomes it&#039;s own unique challenge. To have the outcome of one game impact the next and possible other future games, makes every little decision do matter. 

[imageid=2734332 large]

I won both January and February, got my ass handed to me in March, lost both games. Lost my first game in April, because I realized after my victory I had done a rule wrong, which would have made me lose. Bounced back with a win in the bottom half of the month. I lost both in May, and bounced back again with a win in June. My last three games have come down to the last turn. 

[imageid=2734335 large]

After this is all over. I still won&#039;t pull regular Pandemic out, but I&#039;d surely buy another Legacy Season 1 and play it all over again, even if I knew what it was all about. </body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249616" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="177182" 			
			objectname="Eldritch Horror: Strange Remnants"
			username="tilde72" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 15:32:18 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 15:33:14 +0000"
			thumbs="22"
						imageid="2528391">
	<body>Had my first encounter with Zygygy and the investigators from the Strange Remnants expansion: &quot;Skids&quot; O&#039;Toole, Tony Morgan, Marie Lambeau and Zoey Samaras.

Things were aligned my way, as this became the first major victory in a long time - I wanted an easy journey so I skipped the tentacle mythos cards, and it was pretty rough in the second stage (The Portal Opens) but we held out to the end. I played solo with all four investigators (that is my preferred way to play Eldritch solo).

[imageid=2734364]

Eldritch is a blast to play! With four investigators it&#039;s a lot to keep track of and it&#039;s easy to lose track - the whole game took about 2-3 hours in two sittings :-)

[imageid=2734367]
It&#039;s rough to die in Antarctica...</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249650" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="128445" 			
			objectname="Darkest Night"
			username="RainRaven" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 15:47:36 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 15:47:36 +0000"
			thumbs="26"
						imageid="1432663">
	<body>Finished up my game of Darkest Night I had started last week. It was close but in the end my heroes were overrun by blights. I had managed to get a relic three turns prior or so but the darkness cards had it in for me with creating an extra blight at times. The rogue could not fend off the blights at the monastery. I think the Valkyrie lost at least three turns along the way as well. 

The best compliment I can give the game is that I reset the board afterwards with four new heroes for another play through this week.


[ImageID=2734365]</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249793" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="155700" 			
			objectname="Happy Birthday!"
			username="eastwoodk" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 17:02:34 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 17:02:34 +0000"
			thumbs="29"
						imageid="1943032">
	<body>OK - so it&#039;s not a game I&#039;m playing, but a game that [u][b]YOU [/b][/u]are all going to play. 

Essentially, it&#039;s my birthday month, and I&#039;m going to celebrate by [b]GIVING[/b] a lucky winner something (I&#039;m not saying what it is, because after all that would ruin the surprise. :ninja:

So, what do you need to do?  Simple:

1) Post a comment below on this entry.
2) Tell me what types of games you like to play, and why you like them
3) Tell me what game you loathe
4) Wait until I post a &quot;CLOSED&quot; entry on here
5) If you&#039;re picked, you need to post a comment on here as to what you got.

So, when will it close you may wonder?  Well, my birthday is this month!  So, tick-tock, you&#039;re on the clock!</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4249865" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="169416" 			
			objectname="Pathfinder Adventure Card Game: Wrath of the Righteous – Base Set"
			username="ronster0" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 17:31:19 +0000" 
			editdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 04:47:40 +0000"
			thumbs="25"
						imageid="2564484">
	<body>I loved the original Pathfinder Adventure Card game, but I felt that it could be more. I bought the skull and shackles version, but did not enjoy it and it seemed a bit too overdone. This game definitely ratchets up the difficulty after only two plays. It adds a new mechanic of mythic charges which gives you new powerful attacks and the might D20 to manage. Another game I&#039;d love to play to the end of the campaign in multiplayer, but right now... It&#039;s a solo game.
</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4250091" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="160610" 			
			objectname="Thunderbirds"
			username="wrrlykam" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 19:53:42 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 19:55:09 +0000"
			thumbs="20"
						imageid="2463521">
	<body>Finally got the game on the table, although the dice were missing from the box when I opened it (Chris and Co should have this sorted by the the time I get home). To rub salt in my wounds, I forgot the mocked up dice I made to tide me over. But I found an old copy of Monopoly in the cottage and robbed the dice out of it. 

Game level: INTRO

Started well, drew Alan, Gordon and Penelope and pulled three mission well within their abilities. The Hood started to get a head but the missions were well in hand.

The realisation that it would easier to beat the Hood if I actually turned over the first scheme card did make things move more smoothly.

Worked through the first two Hood schemes and had the the token saved for the final scheme when I drew too many missions that need the final four new pod vehicles. Despite a valiant effort I was short one more turn to get my people in position as the mission slid into the death slot. Game over, IR failed.</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4250330" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="100901" 			
			objectname="Flash Point: Fire Rescue"
			username="HoraceHonkyHorn" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 21:56:37 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 21:57:29 +0000"
			thumbs="21"
						imageid="1129370">
	<body>After losing all my space marines to the red-thing-that-shall-not-be-named in [thing=71721]Space Hulk Death Angel[/thing] earlier, I thought I&#039;d have a go at saving people tonight.

Captain Bob and Generalist Jeff got called out to a house fire at 22 Acacia Avenue. Bob rushed in to take care of the careless inhabitants, while Jeff whipped out his big hose. After [-]dragging[/-] carrying four people out, Bob stopped for tea and sent Nigel the Structural Engineer in to repair some of the damage before the place collapsed. 

Jeff switched over to focus on saving people while Nigel got busy with the gaffa tape. After two more householders were saved, Nigel had done enough so he swapped with Bob again. Several explosions then happened, resulting in two impromptu cremations (N.B. standing next to hazardous material when there&#039;s fire raging isn&#039;t a good idea!). Thankfully Bob and Jeff managed to rescue the remaining victims though, but only just in time, as one more explosion would probably have brought the house down...
[imageid=2734896 medium]
(note the VERY small pile of available damage cubes top centre!)

Six people and Tiddles the cat saved :thumbsup:
Two victims lost :thumbsdown:

R.I.P. Eddie and Albert...
[imageid=2734901 medium]</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4250381" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="186480" 			
			objectname="Die Legenden von Andor: Chada &amp; Thorn – Stinner: Die Solo Erweiterung"
			username="Jan van der Laan" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 22:21:28 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 22:27:48 +0000"
			thumbs="12"
						imageid="2714406">
	<body>Just received this solo expansion together with the base game. Played the first part of the yourney and quite liked it. The rules aren&#039;t very hard and neither is the gameplay but it is a nice &quot;puzzly&quot; type of game and it has quite unusual game mechanics. A scenario is playable in about 30 minutes (though I haven&#039;t played all available scenarios) and set up time is less than a minute. All in all a nice &quot;little&quot; game, nice components and the well known Michael Menzel artwork. Not a game to be played day after day but every once in a while a very enjoyable filler.</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4250518" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="157917" 			
			objectname="The Lord of the Ice Garden"
			username="repairmanjack" 
			postdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 23:54:52 +0000" 
			editdate="Sun, 01 Nov 2015 23:54:52 +0000"
			thumbs="25"
						imageid="2003559">
	<body>Grabbed this second edition from an online UK store - they happily dragged a few copies back from Essen. Set it up tonight and discovered, maddeningly, that I&#039;m missing one of the pieces: no Wyvern. And seeing how imposing it looks in the pics, I&#039;m assuming it&#039;s rather important. 

Wish I&#039;d been able to kickstarter this, but funds and a new baby don&#039;t really stay together too long. I&#039;m hoping I can pick up the Ulf&#039;s Bag extras and the lovely looking stretch goals. (Anyone want to make a sale?)

Anyway, this caught my eye when Ricky Royal demoed the solo mode, which is in the box by design. I&#039;m intrigued by a solo area control (and I had the pious hope it might give me a Game of Thrones thrill, in the absence of four other players). High hopes for it. The board looks fantastic and, unusually, is double-sided; you get a choice of colour-schemes for the map (below you&#039;ll see the dour one, which I seem to prefer). The minis are made of resin, and are quite unlike anything else I&#039;ve handled. I&#039;m told they&#039;re really strong, but they feel like fragile chess pieces in my heavy paws. 

No way I&#039;m reading the rules at ten to midnight, now, but I want this on the table again this week. (Where did my week off go...? Sigh.)

[imageid=2735028large]
[imageid=2735030large]
[imageid=2735033large]
[imageid=2735036large]</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4250591" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="186659" 			
			objectname="Tiny Epic Galaxies Deluxe Edition"
			username="CRB31" 
			postdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:28:42 +0000" 
			editdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 04:54:45 +0000"
			thumbs="18"
						imageid="2714683">
	<body>I got in a three plays of this today, Nov 1.  I am impressed with how it honestly offers a good challenge.  I did win but came close to loosing 2 of the three times.  I am glad I go this one.



Edit: spelling</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4250595" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="166679" 			
			objectname="Elder Sign: Gates of Arkham"
			username="VampyreInABox" 
			postdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:38:19 +0000" 
			editdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:38:19 +0000"
			thumbs="16"
						imageid="2337383">
	<body>[i]Oh look, he played Elder Sign again.[/i]

Yep! It actually hasn&#039;t been placed back in the box since I got it earlier this week. In fact, I liked it so much, I&#039;ve written my second ever BGG review about it. If you&#039;re interested, you can find that over here:

[geekurl=https://boardgamegeek.com/article/20793290]My Elder Sign: Gates of Arkham Review![/geekurl]

I&#039;ve managed to play this with friends yesterday, and I think I might actually even prefer it solo. When I am defeated by an adventure, I like getting back up and trying again, not after other people take their turns. My impatience is a virtue for solo gaming. :cool:

But it made me realize some things that I am thankful for:

[b]I&#039;m thankful[/b] that I rolled a skull on that final die in the one game of this I&#039;ve won.

[b]I&#039;m thankful[/b] that the dog didn&#039;t eat the red die when I got a little excited and overthrew it.

[b]I&#039;m thankful[/b] that the red die doesn&#039;t behave nearly as badly as that evil one in the Space Hulk: Death Angel box. :devil:

[b]I&#039;m thankful[/b] that this is a game that I can concentrate on while I watch football.
[i](Speaking of which, [b]I&#039;m thankful[/b] that the Ravens finally won another game!)[/i]

But, there&#039;s more.

[b]I&#039;m thankful[/b] that this set of GeekLists showed up on the front page for me one day, and led to me to wonderful games that I can enjoy anytime I please.

[b]I&#039;m thankful[/b] for the One Player Guild, for answering my weird questions, making really good recommendations for me, and for dealing with the fact that I&#039;m on this real big Elder Sign kick right now.

[b]I&#039;m thankful[/b] that everyone in this community is pretty great, and for a fun place on the internet to have good conversations about things that I love!

So, thanks! Happy November! I&#039;ll let you know if I ever win this game again. :)</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4250625" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="178613" 			
			objectname="Star Trek: Five-Year Mission"
			username="suzyvitale" 
			postdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 01:00:38 +0000" 
			editdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 03:38:23 +0000"
			thumbs="21"
						imageid="2560621">
	<body>In keeping with the space theme this weekend, I played a game of Star Trek: Five Year Mission with Kirk, Bones and Uhura.  We knocked it out of the park, easily making Admiral.  I ended up with 22 victory points, and 20 is needed for Admiral.  For once, the dice loved me.

This is a light game but I love it so much it&#039;s #3 on my 2015 Top 20 list.  I don&#039;t see it moving from that position.  If you like to chuck dice and you like Star Trek (especially TOS), then you would really like this game.  I think it&#039;s one of the most fun games in my collection.

**Update** Hey Judy, I finally posted [thread=1465122][/thread] to the Star Trek: Five Year Mission forum.  :)</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4250629" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="141572" 			
			objectname="Paperback"
			username="fortheloveofdice" 
			postdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 01:03:59 +0000" 
			editdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 04:25:52 +0000"
			thumbs="18"
						imageid="1991455">
	<body>Finally got a game to the table solo again, and it was this gem.  I may get another game or two in tonight.

It sets up pretty easy, actually.  But somehow that feels like effort.  Once I have it laid out on the table, it is so easy (and tempting) to just play again.

Update: I did get two more games in while I had it out.  Just one more for my 10x10 challenge but I think I want to savor it another day.

I think I&#039;ll start mixing in some of the expansions I don&#039;t normally play with next time.</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4250689" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="119432" 			
			objectname="Snowdonia"
			username="LizzieReads" 
			postdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 02:01:42 +0000" 
			editdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 02:56:40 +0000"
			thumbs="22"
						imageid="1430858">
	<body>With about 40 minutes to kill between Dinner cleanup and the Packer game, I thought a round of Snowdonia would fill that time perfectly. 

It did. 

I&#039;ve played this a handful of times now and this game I scored 172 points which is a game high for me.  I thought I read somewhere that a certain score was a winning score in solo play, but I couldn&#039;t find where I read that (or imagined it). Either way, it felt good to get a high score.  I&#039;m not confident that I&#039;m doing everything correctly.  And I&#039;m confident I&#039;m not doing anything efficiently.  So there is room to grow. But I really like that in a game. I know I can keep working on it and improve my gameplay. 

[imageid=2735149 medium]
So far I&#039;ve enjoyed Snowdonia. Keeping an eye on the weather, contract cards, and build up of resources on the board gives you plenty to think about and manage without getting overly complicated. 

The biggest downside of this game is setting up the rubble cubes. That seems to take almost as long as the entire game.  </body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4250800" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="823" 			
			objectname="Lord of the Rings"
			username="davekuhns" 
			postdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 03:33:48 +0000" 
			editdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 03:33:48 +0000"
			thumbs="19"
						imageid="479124">
	<body>I know it&#039;s nerdy and fanboy-ish, but I am thankful for the Lord of the Rings (books, movies except the Hobbit movies, and now games), it&#039;s brought me much joy!

Well, I don&#039;t have any version with cones. Sorry Gary. It&#039;s still pretty cool looking though! Art by my favorite Tolkien artist John Howe. 
Anyhowe, I have only played this once before, and I really liked it [listitem=3186158]then.[/listitem] Still, getting it out to play and set up just seemed daunting.

[o]It&#039;s not![/o]

That time I played with 4 hobbits. I started Sauron on 15 then (easy mode) and did so as well today. I won more convincingly the last time-had I started Sauron on 12 (normal mode), I would still have won. 
This time, I definitely would have lost, or at least played a little less aggressively. I still died once and backed up 1 turn (of card play only) and still lost Sam to the dark lord. Frodo managed to pull it off though!

[ImageID=2735175large]

:thumbsup: Some how it&#039;s thematically abstract. It&#039;s kind of weird, but it works for me.
:thumbsup: Art and components (even coneless and :sauron:-less) are still beautiful
:thumbsup::thumbsdown: I think it may get samey if played too often, but I think it&#039;s definitely worth breaking out periodically due to the above :thumbsup:s. 


</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4250867" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="183571" 			
			objectname="Deep Space D-6"
			username="settlerdave" 
			postdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 04:03:16 +0000" 
			editdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 04:03:16 +0000"
			thumbs="15"
						imageid="2724490">
	<body>I am thankful for all of the generosity shown by the Guild members in the “The Solo Games Chain of Generosity&quot; Geeklist—I have really enjoyed participating in the chain offerings and I have been able to acquire some great new games.

Speaking of acquiring new games—after I broke down and pledged for [thing=169786][/thing] a week ago, I made a vow to hold off on any more kickstarter pledges or new games until after the fast approaching holiday season. However, this game hit kickstarter on Wednesday and has immediately put my vow to the test. I decided to make the PnP version this weekend and try it out first before backing. I just finished my first play through (see picture below) and thought I could report back my initial impressions to everyone that might be considering backing this game.

[ImageID=2735201 medium]

Even playing the easy mode (all six don’t panic cards in the threat deck), I lost the game when my hull reached 0 with seven cards left in the deck. I was cruising during the early part of the game, but then several turns with no tactical dice led to the buildup of several external threats. When the Nebula threat appeared to knock my shields offline, I was suddenly in big trouble. In the last turn of the game, I had finally managed to eliminate the nebula (you can see the card on the top of the discards at the top of the picture), but a roll of a 5 on the threat die resulted in five damage to the hull. I had reactivated the shields but only had 1 hull point left, so the damage was enough to finish me off.

As for my impressions of the game—well I was pretty damn impressed! The game mechanics were easy to understand and there were some agonizing decisions to be made with how to assign your dice (especially so once the threats start to build up). Given that the kickstarter version of the game will have four ships to play with—basically four potentially very different game variants right in the box—it is likely that my no pledge vow is in trouble.
</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4250881" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="129437" 			
			objectname="Legendary: A Marvel Deck Building Game"
			username="graynoise" 
			postdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 04:07:47 +0000" 
			editdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 04:07:47 +0000"
			thumbs="15"
						imageid="1430769">
	<body>Ive recently been working on a campaign set of rules for Marvel Legendary based on the Golden Solo Variant. I was able to adjust it to work better but I need to try a few more campaigns before its finely tuned. I have been recording all of the play tests: http://boardgamegeek.com/geeklist/198760/marvel-legendary-campaign</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4250933" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="147020" 			
			objectname="Star Realms"
			username="squarepegsys" 
			postdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 04:28:01 +0000" 
			editdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 04:28:01 +0000"
			thumbs="13"
						imageid="1903816">
	<body>Starting off the month with my go-to game.

I&#039;ve been playing the app a lot in October and I like it -- it&#039;s a faithful representation of the game and the Campaign is good to hone your stratedgy. But it&#039;s not the same... I missing the physicality of the &quot;analog&quot; game.

Been awhile since I&#039;ve taken on the Pirates so I gave them a shot. Bought a Merc Cruiser early but I never was able to play it with cards with a Faction. I bought Blobs and a few Federation. I really thought I was sunk but then I got all my Blobs out in one turn. I hit the Pirates for 21 and brought them to zero.

I&#039;m thankful for this guild on convincing me I&#039;m not weird in wanting to play solo games. &quot;Encouragement&quot; isn&#039;t quite right (unless you are talking about lightening my wallet...) but it&#039;s been a good few months hanging out on this guild. And here&#039;s to many more!</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4250966" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="60435" 			
			objectname="Rallyman"
			username="Ulfengaard" 
			postdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 04:47:19 +0000" 
			editdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 04:47:19 +0000"
			thumbs="14"
						imageid="1114034">
	<body>Running Stage 2 of the Monte-Carlo from either &#039;12 or &#039;13 (can&#039;t remember which year the cards come from in the files section). I am running these for the household (all myself, of course). This is the first special. I haven&#039;t run the second and third, yet.

Me: 13:15 (burned SISU already, too :p)
Wife: 15:02 (acceleration ended up entirely borked)
Child 1: 9:45 (I blame luck)
Child 2: 10:36</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4251296" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="177182" 			
			objectname="Eldritch Horror: Strange Remnants"
			username="abendoso" 
			postdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 09:06:43 +0000" 
			editdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 09:06:43 +0000"
			thumbs="13"
						imageid="2528391">
	<body>I finally managed a game of Strange Remnants. I played with the 4 investigators that came in the box and with all expansions mixed in.

The game started very well with my guys rolling good and using their equipment and powers. The first mistery was solved very quickly.

For the second mistery I had to use relics. One of my character had a relic that gave it another Relic so I was cruising very rapidly (quick note, I am not sure I understood the text correctly as I used the relic, turned it, get its benefit and then discard it to gain the advance on the mistery).

But then everything change. The next 2 turns show horrible cards that are an example of the defects of this game. &quot;lose 2 healt AND 2 sanity if you don&#039;t discard an Ally&quot; &quot;lose 3 sanity no-matter-what...&quot; left my investigators with almost no cards and suffering in health.

No problem (I thought) I will go for a win with my 4 investigators to seal the win. I only needed 1 of 4 opportunities. I draw the seal the portal card with my 1st investigator, nice I roll 6 die for the win... missed all of them. 4 monsters appear in the location... At the end of the turn, the 2 men were dead and the 2 women were weakend...

A new turn came up, 1 last chance for the win, the first woman fails to seal the win, but kills all the remaining monsters... and a win on the last chance!

EPIC, but still too random with cards that can hit you out of nowhere with no way to stop them.</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4251628" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="125977" 			
			objectname="Cataclysm: A Second World War"
			username="masil" 
			postdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 14:25:27 +0000" 
			editdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 14:25:27 +0000"
			thumbs="8"
						imageid="1380853">
	<body>I&#039;m thankful for the opportunity given to me to help out with the forthcoming GMT Games title [b]Cataclysm: A Second World War[/b]. This game is on GMT&#039;s P500 list right now. I joined the testing crew recently, put together a PnP copy of the game and now I&#039;ve been getting to know it. I&#039;ve become totally obsessed with this game and so I figured I&#039;d come on SGOYT to tell you about an on-going solo game of mine of Cataclysm.

First of all, what&#039;s the game about? This is a game of politics and war, as the designers William Terdoslavich and Scott Muldoon describe the game, in which the players take the helm of a major world power steering them through a version of WW2 from the diplomatic political build-up into and through the war itself.

One of the key premises of the design has been the ability of the players to create their version of WW2: the familiar elements of the historical conflict are all there from the domestic and international political crises to the military side of it all. Yet, the players are able to recreate an alternative course of events using an impressive array of available game concepts and mechanisms. What results is basically a fascinating vast sandbox for the players to play out [i]a[/i] second world war.

[center][ImageID=2725888 large]
The making of my playtest copy. It&#039;s all non-final playtest art.[/center]

The game sets off with a production phase during which the powers may collect resources available on the map and convert them into a number of types of stuff, e.g. military units or what are called offensive markers that afford the player particular kinds of actions later on in the game. A third important aspect driving the game are the flag tokens affording the players a range of political actions (more of all that below).

I&#039;m soloing all sides in the 2-player introductory scenario called Crisis in the West reenacting the years 1937 through to 1940. In this scenario, the map is limited to the map of Europe only whereas the other scenarios take place on the full world map. The Fascist powers Italy and Germany are allied against the Democratic powers France and the UK. At stake is political control of Europe, with the Fascist sides trailing in points and needing to seize the initiative. A power&#039;s victory point count can consist of a number of things (varying per scenario), but one key measure are the control cubes a power has managed to place in different areas of the map.

[center][ImageID=2735686 large]
[b]Left:[/b] the two halves of the map in Cataclysm. In the scenario I&#039;m playing, the Pacific side of the map is not used. [b]Right:[/b] the US and Canada, the latter as a British colony, are able to provide a very welcome resource boost to the European powers.[/center]

Early on in the game, the goal seems clear: use the production phase to get forces on the map. Actually, they go into a draw cup first from which they emerge randomly during the following action phase.

Later on in the game, when the situation has escalated and more and more stuff is happening on the map, I&#039;m going to face more and more tough choices between using my economy to churn out military machines as opposed to produce upgrade and offensive markers to do things with the stuff that I&#039;ve already got on the board.

Next we&#039;ve got the actions phase. Here you draw random counters, one at a time, from the action cup and the counter&#039;s owner gets to conduct one from a corresponding set of actions. A game turn lasts until all markers have been drawn, or all four so-called crisis markers, that are also in the cup, have been drawn. Upon a Crisis marker being drawn, dice are rolled and a random event occurs potentially bringing a change of pace into the situation.

The first marker or counter I drew was a German flag counter affording this fascist side a political action. The German side could attempt a couple of interesting things here. One option is Diplomacy, the attempt to extend German influence into neighbouring areas to gain a victory point, potentially at the expense of another power&#039;s influence in that area.

And so I went for Diplomacy. The idea was to attempt to reduce the democratic powers&#039; head start by starting a diplomatic offensive against Czechoslovakia to gain access to the resource there as well as to remove the French control cube there.

In this scenario, the German effectiveness is given as three, meaning I&#039;m to roll 3d6 when resolving Diplomacy. The highest roll value achieved using these three dice will be modified by a number of things, including the target country&#039;s resistance value. Czechoslovakia resist foreign influence at level 1 meaning, for Germany to succeed, the highest roll will have to be a 6. This seems like a bit of a gamble but let&#039;s go for it.

Unsurprisingly, Germany fails the check. That&#039;s ok. No provocation results. Provocations fuel conflict in Cataclysm because they afford the provoked powers so-called flags. These are counters with which the powers are able to respond to undertake political, as opposed to military, actions. A power may provoke another by a number of means, such as by successfully spreading its diplomatic influence into an area in which another power has interest, a neighbouring area, for instance. Failed diplomacy does not count as a provocation.

[center][ImageID=2735685 large]
[b]Top left:[/b] the Spanish civil war as depicted in Cataclysm. The Fascist powers, Germany and Italy, support the right nationalist side in the war by offering Foreign Aid (the arrow counters to the right of the civil war marker). At stake is political influence in Spain and ultimately victory points. [b]Top right:[/b] Rearmament in Europe. Armies, air force and fleets dot the landscape. Who&#039;s going to make the first move? [b]Bottom:[/b] the Red Army is about to roll into Poland.[/center]

On we go. The play proceeded quite fast as I kept drawing more markers most of which are quite quick to resolve. During this build-up phase, the powers take opportunities to build up their political influence but also to secure it by moving forces into friendly countries. Basically, you&#039;re wanting to get provoked so that you receive more political capital (flag counters) to get stuff done (and inevitably provoke the other powers).

At one point I pulled the French Home Front marker. This marker triggers what&#039;s called a Home Front check. This simulates the development of the mood at home when the power in question has reached a certain more aggressive commitment level. The French were at Rearmament level and therefore subject to a Home Front check which they failed. As a result, the French stability sank from wavering to unstable. The nation seemed to be crumbling under the weight of the European-wide power struggle. Right away I played a French flag from the reserve ---a sort of an emergency fund from which a previously reserved marker can be drawn almost at will to get one really important thing done. I used the flag to do Propaganda, a political action, to shore up some stability at home in which the French succeeded.

In this scenario, the Soviet Union functions as a non-player side conducting random aggressions in certain countries. In my game, the Soviet dummy came to attack neutral Poland. At this point I began to regret that I had not deployed any French armies into Poland to protect the French control cube in there. Now it threatened to be too late as the Soviets were rolling into Poland. We had some combat to resolve.

In Cataclysm, combat involves some die rolling, with modifiers where applicable. As a result, losses may be suffered and/or units withdrawn. In the present case, due to some lucky rolls, the Polish were able to withstand the Soviet attack. The French got lucky, for now, and kept their foothold in Poland.

As a result of the Soviet aggression, however, the special game state called Status Quo got broken giving the two Democratic powers in play, the French and the UK, immediately a flag each plus boosting their earnings during the production phase. Basically, the Soviet aggression opened the flood gates a little and the Democratic powers would now also be able to prepare for war at heightened ability.

Soon I drew a so-called Civil War Resolution marker. This triggered the end game of the on-going Spanish civil war. A round of combat got resolved and it ended for the benefit of the Fascist sides. The next German or Italian attempt at Diplomacy toward Spain would be a little more likely to succeed with a +1 DRM boosting the attempt. As it happens, the next chit I pull is a German flag affording them just the Diplomacy action they needed now. 

In this reenactment of WW2, the Germans had already occupied Sweden and now they were going to use the nationalist victory in Spain to extend their political influence there. I was rewriting history.

How were the Democratic powers going respond? Earlier on, the UK had spent a political action, but to no avail, to attempt to persuade the US to lend resources to help counter the rising Fascist threat in Europe. The US giant remained asleep, for now at least. Should Germany succeed in Spain, more provocation still would result affording the Democratic sides more opportunities to respond. This game has just begun. We haven&#039;t really even touched the combat side of the game yet.

I hope that gives everyone a small taster of the kind of game Cataclysm is. Stay tuned for updates!
</body>
	
		</item>
	<item id="4251717" 
			objecttype="thing"
			subtype="boardgame" 
			objectid="2511" 			
			objectname="Sherlock Holmes Consulting Detective"
			username="garyrbrooks" 
			postdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 14:55:47 +0000" 
			editdate="Mon, 02 Nov 2015 14:56:44 +0000"
			thumbs="7"
						imageid="1977064">
	<body>I played the second case and I managed to solve it but only after chasing a whole number of leads that went nowhere. Final score was 10 and you need 100+ to beat Holmes.

[ImageID=2735708 medium]The tools of the trade.

This is like nothing else I own and that&#039;s a good thing.  Just a paper, pen and my brain (which isn&#039;t so hot) are needed.

Beating Holmes is a dream but solving the case is possible and so as long as you don&#039;t mind not beating the great detective you will have a good time.  It is even fun following a red herring as you get so much story to go with it.

[user=rangerx][/user] inspired me to say my thanks to you all over here: [b][thread=1464846][/thread][/b].  But I will say it again anyway, thank you.

However, I also want to say [b]thank you to my wife[/b] for putting up with me and this hobby over the last 2 years as well as being the driving force behind Dunshire (my future games room).  It&#039;s possibly a plan to just keep me and my geekiness out of the way but I decided to keep a log of the work on it here:

[b][geeklist=199014][/geeklist][/b]

I&#039;d like to also say thanks to [user=bikefreak][/user] as I&#039;m copying his brilliant [geeklist=191749][/geeklist] geeklist idea.</body>
	
		</item>
</geeklist>
